Guide to the J. Walter Thompson Company. Broadcast Business Affairs records, 1934-1976 and undated RL.11166
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company. Broadcast Business Affairs records
1934-1976 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company
John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
RL.11166
4.5 Linear Feet
Founded in 1864, the J. Walter Thompson Company (JWT) is one of the oldest and largest enduring advertising agencies in the United States.
Arrangement
Arranged alphabetically.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The J. Walter Thompson Company. Broadcast Business Affairs records were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 1993.
Related Materials
Related materials may be found in the following JWT Archives collections held in the Hartman Center: Account Files; Bill Lane papers; John F. Devine papers; Maury Holland papers; Radio and Television Department records.
Collection Overview
Consists of memoranda, correspondence, legal agreements and other printed materials. Companies represented include American Gas Association, Ford, Kodak, Kraft, Pan Am, and R.T. French. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Advertising agencies -- United States; Advertising -- Television programs; J. Walter Thompson Company; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
- American Gas Association--Various special programs, 1969-1973; 4 folders (Box 1)
- BAR (Broadcast Advertisers Report) memos, 1973 (Box 1)
- Eastman Kodak--1972 Summer Olympics, 1972-1973 (Box 1)
- Eastman Kodak--A Man Without a Country, 1972-1973 (Box 2)
- Eastman Kodak--America's Junior Miss Pageant, 1971-1974; 4 folders (Box 2)
- Eastman Kodak--America's Junior Miss Pageant, 1975 (Box 3)
- Eastman Kodak--Junior Miss, 1976 (Box 3)
- Eastman Kodak--Stars and Stripes, 1974-1975; 2 folders (Box 3)
- Ford--Bob Hope specials/Christmas show, 1972-1973 (Box 3)
- Ford--Bob Hope specials/Desert Classic, 1973-1974; 2 folders (Box 4)
- Ford--Going Up of David Lev, 1972-1973; 2 folders (Box 4)
- Ford--NFC football, 1973-1975; 2 folders (Box 4)
- Ford--Sports Special of the Month, 1976 (Box 4)
- Ford--The Lively Ones, 1963-1964 (Box 5)
- Kraft Foods--Edward J. Herlihy, 1956-1970; 2 folders (Box 5)
- Kraft Foods--Kraft Music Hall, 1970; 3 folders (Box 6)
- Kraft Foods--Kraft Theater, 1949-1958; 2 folders (Box 6)
- Kraft Foods--Legal, 1966 (Box 6)
- Kraft Foods--Perry Como, 1966-1967 (Box 6)
- Kraft Foods--Road West, 1966 (Box 6)
- Kraft Foods--Signed agreement material, 1959-1964 (Box 6)
- Kraft Foods--Special programs, 1972-1973 (Box 7)
- Memoranda, 1973-1974 (Box 7)
- NBC integration, 1977 (Box 7)
- Pan Am--1972 Winter Olympics (Box 7)
- R.T. French--Daytime television programming, 1964 (Box 7)
- Speakeasy syndication agreement, undated (Box 7)
- Talent and miscellaneous agreements, 1974-1975 (Box 7)
- New York Broadcasting Department programs and sponsors, 1934-1959 (Box 8)
- New York Broadcasting Department talent, music and contact cards, 1936-1962 (Box 8)